Preliminary Guide to the Walter Edwin Peck Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Walter Edwin Peck papers
1830-1930
MS 390
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.5
(8 boxes)
The papers consist almost entirely of research materials and a Ph.D. thesis on Percy Bysshe Shelley together with typescript and galley-proofs of books about Shelley written by Walter Edwin Peck and published in 1926 and 1927. Among the small amount of personal papers are a diary for 1907, photographs, correspondence and memorabilia. Two account books from Ashtabula, Ohio (1830-1847) are also included.
Peck, Walter Edwin, 1891-1954
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Gabriel Wells in 1937.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Walter Edwin Peck Papers are completely unprocessed. They consist of manuscripts, typescripts, and galley proofs of writings by Peck about Percy Bysshe Shelley, notes and notebooks about Shelley compiled by Peck while at Oxford, and assorted printed matter about Shelley. These materials for the most part were used by Peck for Shelley, His Life and Work(1927) and The Complete Works of Percy Bysshe Shelley(1926; co-editor Roger Ingpen). There is also a typescript of Peck's 1922 Oxford Ph.D. thesis on Shelley, and notes and assorted papers on various other romantic poets. Also among the papers is a smaller amount of memorabilia and newspaper clippings pertaining to Peck's activities while at Ashtabula (Ohio) High School, Wooster College and Hamilton College. Included here are several scrap-books, a college yearbook, postcards and photgraphs from Italy and a small amount of correspondence. Two of the scrapbooks are account books from the 1830s and 1840s into which Peck pasted memorabilia.
Biographical / Historical
Author; M.A., Columbia, 1918; Ph.D., Oxford, 1922; 1924-1926, taught at Wesleyan University; 1926-1927, head of the English Department of Washington State College; 1927-1929 taught at Hunter College.
Literature -- History and criticism; Ashtabula (Ohio); Account books; Educators; Peck, Walter Edwin, 1891-1954; Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822
- Inventory, 1830-1847, 1882 [ca. 1900-1930]
  - Oxford College Notebooks, 1920-1922
    - 6 notebooks containing a transcription of Zofloya the Moor by Mrs. Charlotte Byrne, 1806 (Box 1)
    - 4 notebooks on Shelley (Box 1)
    - Notebooks and conversations with Robert Graves and Roger Ingpen (Box 1)
  - Loose notes on Shelley (Box 1)
  - Typescript of Peck's Oxford Ph.D. thesis on Shelley, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Typescript of Peck's Oxford Ph.D. thesis on Shelley, 1922 (Box 3)
  - Other typescripts and loose notes on Shelley (Box 3)
  - Will of Edwin O. Peck, 1882 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence concerning research on Shelley and letters to the editot about Shelley, 1915-1929 (Box 3)
  - Printed matter about Shelley, 1920-1930 (Box 3)
  - Postcards and photographs from Italy (Box 4)
  - Notecards on Shelley (Box 4)
  - Typescripts, manuscripts, and notes about Shelley (Box 4)
  - Printed matter about Shelley, 1920-1930 (Box 4)
  - Notebook on Shelley (Box 4)
  - Galley proofs of book by Peck on Shelley, 1927(?) (Box 4)
  - Notebook on Shelley (Box 5)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Bill book of Henry Harris of Ashtabula Ohio, used as scrapbook by Peck, containing clippings, memorabilia, etc., 1830-1839, 1908-1918 (Box 5)
    - Account book of unidentified Ashtabula Ohio, doctor, used as scrapbook by Peck, containing photographs, correspondence, memorabilia, etc.; and used as a diary for the year 1907, 1844-1847, 1907-1920 (Box 6)
    - Blank scrapbook (Box 6)
  - Hamilton College yearbook, 1912 (Box 6)
  - 4 notebooks on Shelley (Box 7)
  - Galley proofs of book on Shelley (Box 8)
  - Printed matter on Shelley, 1920-1930 (Box 8)
  - Memorabilia and newspaper clippings about Peck, 1900-1930 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook containing memorabilia, 1910-1920 (Box 8)
  - Card file on Shelley (Box 9)